Dave, do you mind if I ask
you a personal question?
No, not at all.
I’ve wondered whether
you might be having some
second thoughts about
the mission.
How do you mean?
Rumours about something
being dug up on the moon.
I never gave these
stories much credence.
But, particularly
in view of some of the
other things that
have happened...
I find them difficult
to put out of my mind.
[eerie tone]
Open the pod bay doors
please, HAL.
Open the pod bay doors, HAL.
I’m sorry, Dave.
I’m afraid I can’t do that.
What are you talking
about, HAL?
This conversation can
serve no purpose anymore.
Goodbye.
[eerie tone]
[eerie tone continues]
[music crecendos]
[triumphant music]
[triumphant music continues]